Guide to the The Chronicle records, 1904-2000
Duke University. University Archives
The Chronicle records 1904-2000
Duke University. University Archives
Chronicle (Durham, N.C.)
2.9 linear feet Extent: 3000 Items
The Chronicle is Duke's independent, student-run news publication. Originally financed by the Columbian and Hesperian Literary Societies, the newspaper is currently (2007) completely independent of the University, and funded entirely by advertising revenue. Materials in the collection include letters to the editors, correspondence, submitted material, awards, illustrations, historical documents and notes, schedules, calendars, reports, flyers, forms, surveys and questionnaires, meeting minutes, and releases. The materials date from 1904-2000, the bulk of which is from 1950-1970.
UA.31.01.0002
Language: Material in English
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
Collection is open for research.
Provenance
The The Chronicle records were received by the University Archives as a transfer in 1971-1988.
Historical Note
The Chronicle is Duke's independent, student-run news publication. Actually older than the University itself, the Chronicle was founded December 9, 1905 at Duke University's predecessor Trinity College. Trinity College became Duke University in 1924, and the newspaper continued to cover campus news and the world around it. The Chronicle was first realized as a weekly newspaper, but by the middle of the century had twice evolved into a bi-weekly and then a tri-weekly publication. In 1968, the paper was finally expanded into a weekday daily.
Originally financed by the Columbian and Hesperian Literary Societies, the newspaper was later financed by student subscription fees and advertisements. Currently (2007), it is completely independent of the University, and funded entirely by advertising revenue.
For a more in-depth history of the Chronicle please see the University Archives web exhibit: The Chronicle: 100 years of a student newspaper http://library.duke.edu/uarchives/exhibits/chronicle/index.html
Collection Overview
Materials in the collection include letters to the editors, correspondence, submitted material, awards, illustrations, historical documents and notes, schedules, calendars, reports, flyers, forms, surveys and questionnaires, meeting minutes, and releases. The materials date from 1904-2000, the bulk of which is from 1950-1970.
Subject Headings
Chronicle (Duke University: 1925); Chronicle (Durham, N.C.: 1970); Duke chronicle; Duke University -- Periodicals; Trinity chronicle.
Related Material
Columbian and Hesperian Literary Societies’ records, 1848-1942.
University Archives, Duke University.
James Patrick Toomey papers, 1981-1983.
University Archives, Duke University.
Index to the Chronicle, Duke University, Durham, NC / [serial].
University Archives, Duke University.
Index to the Trinity College and Duke University Chronicle, v.1, 1905-v.29, 1933
University Archives, Duke University.
Through these doors: 100 years of the Chronicle
University Archives, Duke University.
The Trinity chronicle [serial].
University Archives, Duke University.
Contents of Collection
- Letters to the Editor, 1955-1970, 2 Boxes
  - Letters to the Editor, 1955-1956 (Box 1)
  - Letters to the Editor, 1956-1957 (Box 1)
  - Letters to the Editor, 1957-1958 (Box 1)
  - Letters to the Editor, 1958-1959 (Box 1)
  - Letters to the Editor, 1960-1961 (Box 1)
  - Letters to the Editor, 1961-1962 (Box 1)
  - Letters to the Editor [Nelson Administration], 1963 (Box 1)
  - Letters to the Editor, 1965-1966 (Box 1)
  - Letters to the Editor [Not Used], 1966-1967 (Box 2)
  - Letters to the Editor (1), 1966-1967 (Box 2)
  - Letters to the Editor (2), 1966-1967 (Box 2)
  - Letters to the Editor (3), 1966-1967 (Box 2)
  - Letters to the Editor (1), 1967-1968 (Box 2)
  - Letters to the Editor (2), 1967-1968 (Box 2)
  - Letters to the Editor [Not Used], 1969-1970 (Box 2)
- Correspondence, 1966-1969, 1 Box
  - Correspondence, 1966-1967 (Box 3)
  - Correspondence, 1967-1968 (Box 3)
  - Correspondence, 1968-1969 (Box 3)
- Submitted Material, 1967-1968, 1 Box
  - Submitted Material (1), 1967-1968 (Box 3)
  - Submitted Material (2), 1967-1968 (Box 3)
  - Submitted Material (3), 1967-1968 (Box 3)
- Subject files, 1904-2000, 2 Boxes
  - 75th Anniversary Reunion (1), November 1980 (Box 4)
  - 75th Anniversary Reunion (2), November 1980 (Box 4)
  - Advisory Program, 1968 (Box 4)
  - Awards, 1939-1970 (Box 4)
  - Bethany Sue Strong Sinnott, Letter, 1980 (Box 4)
  - Chronicle Organization, ca. 1968 (Box 4)
  - "Duke by DePree", 1984-1988 (Box 4)
  - History (1), 1948-1966 (Box 4)
  - History (2), 1905-1938 (Box 4)
  - Letters from Former Editors and Other Material, 1980 (Box 4)
  - List of Editors and Business Managers, 1904-1935 (Box 4)
  - "Prince Quirky", 2000 (Box 4)
  - Trinity College Governing Board of Trinity Chronicle Minutes, 1908-1920 (Box 4)
  - Candidates, Etc., 1968 (Box 5)
  - Columns, 1976-1977 (Box 5)
  - Etc., 1959, 1967 (Box 5)
  - Organization and Recruitment, 1968-1969 (Box 5)
  - Project Coordination, 1968-1969 (Box 5)
  - Report of the Antioch College Commission on Governance, 1968 (Box 5)
  - Residential Reform, 1968 (Box 5)
  - Trimester Report, Etc., 1963 (Box 5)
  - Wire Information, 1968 (Box 5)